Waldo Lavaut 8977 SW 123rd court apt106, Miami FL 33186 786-521-3075 waldothedeveloper@gmail.com waldothedeveloper.com

https://github.com/waldothedeveloper

SUMMARY

More than 5 years programming and application development experience.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages

 Proficient in: Ruby, Python, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript (including ES6), React JS, Git & GitHub, JSON, SQL, MVC, Agile, Bootstrap, Material-UI, SharePoint Design and Development, Fabric UI.

EXPERIENCE

SharePoint Web Software Developer Associate

Conviva Care Solutions (June 2019 - Present)

- Continuous development integration collaboration within the SharePoint developer's team implementing highly scalable and interchangeable full stack features using React web components for the mimo.convivasolutions.com website.
- Incorporating core new features such as form request submissions, full text web search and UI-UX of the MIMO website integrated to SharePoint, Microsoft Flow and online Excel to automate and reduce time cost efficiency by 38% for the Business Analyst's team.

IT Support Help Desk Level II

- Conviva Care Solutions (March 2019 June 2019)
- Writing efficient and high performant PowerShell scripts for effectively managing the large Corporate Active Directory and Exchange Database of Conviva, automating manual bulk CRUD operations to increase productivity by 60%.
- General IT technical support related to desktop computer systems, a large variety of proprietary software such as ECW v11, MdVita, Chameleon, and hardware equipment such as Lexmark printers, ADP time clock machines, Polycom VoIP phones and Enterprise Unified Endpoint Solutions such as Blackberry UEM.
- Troubleshoot WAN and LAN network issues related to file servers, FortiClient VPN access, Cisco
 and Netgear switchers connectivity and latency issues, performing remote software updates and
 identify and isolate network performance issues.

IT Support Help Desk Level I

- Quantum Technology Partners (Dec 2017 March 2019)
- Troubleshoot iOS users working with the Blackberry Suite Enterprise Apps.
- Managed more than 2000 users within Microsoft Server 2012 and 2016 Active Directory Module
 writing PowerShell script to automate daily tasks like creating or disabling users.

Web Developer Associate

Kipu Systems (September 2016 - December 2017)

- Developed scripts using NodeJS and Ruby to help clients communicate with the company's API
- Learned about software development and implementation in the medical field.
- Increased my SCRUM knowledge and Agile methodologies by actively participating in daily scrum meetings.

- Applied TDD methodologies, wrote Rspec and Capybara tests to assure the expected behavior or different parts of the application.
- Worked on solving bugs with the Health-matters dev team which helped me to improve my debugging process.

Frontend Developer at University of Arts, Havana Cuba.

Conviva Care Solutions (March 2014 - August 2016)

- Developing responsive HTML, CSS and JavaScript forms used internally by the University's International Relationships department.
- Weekly updates to the NoSQL Document Database in the University's news website (http://www.isa.cult.cu/noticias/)
- Upgrading specialized software such as Finale Music Software and Reason in the Electroacoustics department hosted in Windows 7 OS and MacOS Mountain Lion.

EDUCATION

Miami, Florida - 2016

• FreeCodeCamp Bootcamp

Miami, Florida - 2017 & 2018

- Wyncode Academy Bootcamp
- Launch Code LC101 Summer 2018 Bootcamp 2018